educationperfect.com 2014-03-05

# Privacy - EP World Series

**Language Perfect Ltd Privacy Policy**  
  
Language Perfect cares deeply about the safety, security and privacy of our users. Please read below for further information about your privacy on our site. By using Language Perfect, you accept the terms of this policy.  
  
 _(“Language Perfect”, “we”, and “us” are used synonymously in this document to refer to Language Perfect Ltd)._  

Our Guiding Principles  

  * We don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it.
  * We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law or protect our rights (see below).
  * As many of our users are children and young adults, we actively protect their privacy and safety above and beyond what would be expected for adults. Our goal is to provide a learning environment that is every bit as safe and secure as being at school.

What personal information we collect  
  
When we register a school we require the following information about each student to create their accounts:  

  *  **First**  and  **surnames**
  * An  **enduring identifier**  such as a school ID (required so that student profiles can be carried over from year to year)
  *  **Classes**  that each student is in

When a teacher registers their students they give consent for us to collect this data and for their students to participate on Language Perfect. Prior to sending us any personal information about their students, it is the teacher and school's responsibility to ensure that:  

  * they have followed all appropriate school policies and guidelines; and
  * the students concerned have authorised the collection of the information and where the students are under the age of 13 the students’ parents/guardians have authorised the collection of the information.

If students choose not to give personal information to us, they will not be able to participate on Language Perfect.  
  
When a student first logs in to Language Perfect, we strongly encourage them to change the generic password that they have been provided with. When they do this they are required to enter an  **email address** , so that we can send them a new password should they forget this one.  
  
What we do with your personal informationLanguage Perfect uses the information that we collect from our users to:  

  * Identify students to their teachers and peers
  * Reset a user’s password when requested
  * Gather and respond to feedback and reports of technical problems
  * Publish names of competition leaders and winners on our scoreboards. (See also the section on ‘Privacy of children’)

Anonymous / Aggregate information  
  
Language Perfect collects statistics about how you use our site for the purpose of improving our product. For example, we might record how long it takes our users to answer different types of questions so that we can determine how many points to allocate to each question. This information will only ever be used as aggregate (grouped) data which will not contain personally-identifying information.  
We also reserve the right to gather aggregate, non-personally-identifying data for other purposes such as educational research.  
  
Emails  
  
Language Perfect may occasionally send you an email. We realise that your inbox is already too full and try to keep these to a minimum. Some examples of these messages include:  

  * An email to tell you your new password if you were to forget your old one
  * A message reminding you about upcoming due work
  * A message with details of upcoming school competitions
  * A message congratulating you on achieving a milestone in one of our competitions

You can easily opt out of receiving these emails by following the instructions at the bottom of each message.  
  
What we will not do with your personal information  
  
Language Perfect will keep your personal information confidential, and will not rent, sell or knowingly divulge your information to any third party, other than in circumstances expressly permitted under relevant privacy laws.  
  
Privacy of children  
  
Language Perfect recognises that many of our users are children and young adults, and that as such are potentially vulnerable on the internet. Our goal is to provide a learning environment that is every bit as safe and secure as being at school.  
A student’s full name and score is only visible to their peers (other students in their class). Teachers can only access the information and results of students attending their school.  
  
Public scoreboards  
  
Our users take great joy in seeing themselves excelling on our global scoreboards. To identify our users on these scoreboards we use their First names, the first letter of their surnames, the school they attend and which country their school is based in (e.g. Joe B, Saint Kentigern College, New Zealand). We feel that this strikes a balance between enabling our users to easily identify themselves to their friends and family, and protecting their identities from unwanted attention on the internet.  
  
Keeping your personal information secure  
  
The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us. However, no data storage or transfer mechanism is 100% secure, hence we cannot absolutely guarantee the security of your information.  
It is your responsibility to ensure that your access details (username and password) are kept private and to inform us if you believe that the security of your account has been breached.  
  
How you can manage your personal information  
  
If you would like to update or correct any of your (or your child or student’s) personal information, or if you would like your information removed from our system entirely, please send an email us at[support@languageperfect.com](mailto:support@languageperfect.com) and we will happily do so.  
  
Technical details  
  
Storage and transfer of data  
  
Language Perfect’s servers are hosted in Sydney, Australia by Amazon Web Services Inc. (head office: 410 Terry Ave. North, Seattle, WA 98109-5210). We are a New Zealand company and all of our staff are based in New Zealand. As such, your data will by necessity be transferred between Australia and New Zealand to be viewed, processed and updated by our staff. We have no data presence outside of Australia and New Zealand, and will not transfer your data outside of these countries.  
  
Cookies  
  
A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor's computer, and that the visitor's browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Language Perfect uses cookies to identify visitors to our servers across different pages in our site. We do not use third-party cookies to track your internet browsing beyond our site. Language Perfect visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using our website, with the drawback that certain features of Language Perfect’s website may not function properly without the aid of cookies.  
  
Links  
  
Language Perfect will occasionally link to external websites. We have no control over the content or privacy policies of these sites. External links are followed at the user’s own risk.  
  
Data retention  
  
Language Perfect will retain your information for 3 years after you cease to use our service, unless you specifically request for us to remove it prior to that.  
  
Revision Policy  
  
Language Perfect may change this policy from time to time. We will post any privacy policy changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice. If you wish to be notified about all changes to our privacy policy, please email [support@languageperfect.com](mailto:support@languageperfect.com). You are deemed to have consented to any changes to this policy by your continued use of the site.  
  
Relevant Legislation  
  
Our privacy policy complies with the National Privacy Principles of the Australian Commonwealth Privacy Act (1988) and New Zealand’s Privacy Act (1993).  
  
For more information about your privacy please see:  

  * New Zealand: [http://www.privacy.org.nz](http://www.privacy.org.nz/)
  * Australia: [http://www.privacy.gov.au](http://www.privacy.gov.au/)

Contact Details  
  
Physical Location  
504 George Street  
Dunedin  
New Zealand

Email [support@languageperfect.com](mailto:support@languageperfect.com)

Phone

NZ   +64 3 669 0311  
AUS +61 2 6100 3723  
UK   +44 20 8816 8363  
US   +1 (202) 657 5224

Mail  
Language Perfect  
PO Box 6552  
North Dunedin  
Dunedin 9059  
New Zealand
